EMAIL SUPPORT SPECIALIST

Profile

To effectively demonstrate my leadership, communication, and technical skills in a professional environment supporting businesses with opportunity for growth and advancement. Positive and energetic, able to energize others Leadership experience Phone, chat, and email service experience Passion for customers Experience working cross-departmentally Advanced troubleshooting experience Can work independently, prefers team setting

Skills

Microsoft Windows and Apple OS, including common networking protocols and security software Software proficiencies - Advanced MS Office, Advanced Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign), Intermediate Visual Studio (HTML/CSS/Java), support ticketing systems

Professional Experience

Matthews International January 2010 to January 2013 Email Support Specialist

- Responsible for launching the first global support team for HP Cloud Services over Chat and Email support channels.
- Recruited, trained, and mentored high-potential agents for the new team to ensure a superior customer experience.
- Designed, documented, and implemented the core process framework governing the team's customer support interactions.
- Assisted customers directly with advanced technical issues related to HP Cloud Services.
- Key Achievements: Drove team-wide performance improvements in every key metric ranging from 20% to 60% through comprehensive process redesign, hands-on implementation, and relentless iterative execution.
- Led the team to the highest-ranked spot in the HP global enterprise for chat/email support, holding that spot concurrently for nearly 2 years.
- Awards received: Highest Cloud Chat/Email Performer 2012, Extra Mile award, and "WOW" award, among other accolades for performance, passion, productivity, innovation, leadership, and values.
- Earned the highest possible performance review rating each year in role.

Logoworks LLC January 2009 to January 2010 Technical Solutions Representative

- Responsible for resolving advanced technical issues related to HP printers for small and medium business customers, including hardware, software, and networking issues.
- Trained and mentored other agents in matters of policy, process, sales, call efficiency, and technical resolution.
- Key Achievements: Received the Extra Mile award for consistently going above and beyond role responsibilities, including driving continuous process and quality improvements.
- Recognized by site leadership for continuously mentoring agents on numerous teams throughout the organization.
- Earned the highest possible performance review rating for fiscal year 2011.

John Brown University January 2007 to January 2008 Graphic/Web Designer

- Responsible for designing innovative print and web solutions for Logoworks clients.
- Used strong interpersonal skills to uncover customers' underlying needs and employed proven design methodologies to solve their unique visual communication problems.
- Used Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, and Indesign to design logos, advertising, signage, brochures, and more.
- Used HTML, CSS, and Java to design custom websites based on clients' unique individual business needs.
- Key Achievements: Mentored and developed other designers within the organization, leading to increased departmental performance, efficiency, and both customer/employee satisfaction.
- Championed for innovative process improvements leading to 25% faster turnaround times for the entire design team.
- Recognized by company leadership as the top-performing designer in the organization.
- Web Design Work-Study Responsible for designing fresh web solutions for University clients along with managing routine website maintenance and updates.
- Key Achievements: Led, trained, and mentored other work-study students in basic HTML, CSS, and Java in order to foster enhanced learning opportunities and overall departmental design quality.
- Streamlined work-study operations including intensive process redesign and strategic realignment increasing workorder turnaround speed and overall departmental efficiency by over 30%.

Education and Training

Jack Welch Management Institute at Strayer University 2015 Master of Business Administration (MBA)

John Brown University 2008 Bachelor of Science: Digital Media Arts Digital Media Arts

Skills

Adobe Creative Suite, Photoshop, Adobe Photoshop, advertising, Apple, brochures, strong interpersonal skills, hardware, crisis management, CSS, clients, customer support, designing, driving, Email, finance, HP, HP printers, hiring, HTML, basic HTML, Illustrator, Indesign, innovation, Java, leadership, logos, managing, mentoring, MS Office, Microsoft Windows, enterprise, networking, OS, operations management, process design, protocols, quality, sales, strategic, unique, Visual Studio, Web Design, website, websites